Flemish Painting Photograph Collection
Yale University Arts Library
Flemish Painting Photograph Collection
1900-2005
VRC 19
Yale University Arts Library
25.8
62 boxes
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Flemish paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders. For 19th-20th century painting, see the Belgian painting Photograph Collection.
Conditions Governing Access
These materials are stored offsite at the Library Shelving Facility. For access to the materials, please make a request at the Art & Architecture Library.
Arrangement
Organized alphabetically by individual artist name. The individual artist material is further divided primarily by location of work. The individual artist portion is preceded by grouping arranged chronologically and sub-arranged by artists identified as "Master of... ".
Scope and Contents
Collection of mounted black and white and color reproductions of Flemish paintings. Content varies from original photographic prints to reproductions from magazines and other published sources. Some sections have accompanying clippings folders. For 19th-20th century painting, see the Belgian painting Photograph Collection.
Painting, Flemish; Photographs; Reproductions
- Anonymous. (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Includes a folder of miscellaneous clippings.
  - Unknown artists, unknown dates., 5 (Box 1)
  - XVI Century., 3 (Box 1)
  - XV Century., 73 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous works., 45 (Box 1)
    - Master of the St. Lucy Legend., 13 (Box 1)
    - Master of St. Gudule, active 1489., 5 (Box 2)
    - Master of the St. Ursula Legend., 5 (Box 2)
    - Master of the Tiburtine Sybil, active 1480-1495., 5 (Box 2)
  - XVI Century., 56 (Box 2)
    - Miscellaneous works., 42 (Box 2)
    - Master of Frankfort., 8 (Box 2)
    - Master of the Half-Length Figures, active 1540., 6 (Box 2)
  - XVII Century., 9 (Box 3)
- A (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Artists A., 3 (Box 3)
    - Achtscellinck, Lucas, 1626-1699., 1 (Box 3)
    - Aelst, Pieter Coecke van, 1502-1550., 1 (Box 3)
    - Avont, Peeter van, 1600-1631., 1 (Box 3)
  - Individual Artists A., 4 (Box 3)
    - Arthois, Jacques d', 1613-1686., 4 (Box 3)
- B (Box 3)
  - Miscellaneous Artists B., 20 (Box 3)
    - Baren, Johannes Antonius van der, 1615-1686., 1 (Box 3)
    - Beer, Jan de, 1475-c.1528., 1 (Box 3)
    - Beich, Joachim Franz, 1665-1748., 1 (Box 3)
    - Bellechose, Henri, active 1415-1440., 1 (Box 3)
    - Biset, C.E., 1633-1691., 1 (Box 3)
    - Bloeman, Pieter van, 1657-1720., 1 (Box 3)
    - Blondeel, Lancelot, 1498-1561., 1 (Box 3)
    - Boel, Peeter, 1622-1674., 2 (Box 3)
    - Boeyermans, Theodor, 1620-1678., 1 (Box 3)
    - Borcht, Pieter van der, active 1552-1608., 1 (Box 3)
    - Bosch, B. van den, 1681-1715., 1 (Box 3)
    - Boucquet, Victor, 1619-1677., 1 (Box 3)
    - Boudewyns, Adriaen, 1644-1711., 1 (Box 3)
    - Bout, Pieter, 1658-1719., 2 (Box 3)
      One work done with Adriaen Boudewyns.
    - Bouts, Aelbrecht, 1460-1549., 2 (Box 3)
    - Braunschweiger Monogrammist, XVI C., 1 (Box 3)
    - Broeck, Crispin van den, 1534-1591., 1 (Box 3)
  - Individual Artists B., 589 (Box 3)
    - Balen, Hendrik van, 1575-1632., 7 (Box 3)
    - Beert, Osias the Elder, active 1596-1624., 4 (Box 3)
    - Benson, Ambrosius, active 1519-1550., 10 (Box 3)
    - Bles, Henri Met de, 1480-1550., 19 (Box 3)
    - Bloemen, Jan Frans van, 1662-1749., 5 (Box 3)
    - Bol, Hans, 1534-1593., 6 (Box 4)
    - Bosch, Hieronymus, 1450-1516., 82 (Box 4)
      Includes a large folder of miscellaneous clippings.
      - Miscellaneous cities., 23 (Box 4)
      - Ghent., 9 (Box 5)
      - Lisbon., 8 (Box 5)
      - Madrid., 36 (Box 5)
        - Garden of Earthly Delights Triptych, 21 (Box 5)
      - Vienna., 6 (Box 5)
    - Bouts, Dirck, 1410/20-1475., 59 (Box 6)
      - Locations not noted., 5 (Box 6)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 30 (Box 6)
      - London., 6 (Box 6)
      - Louvain., 11 (Box 6)
      - Paris., 7 (Box 6)
    - Bril, Paul, 1554-1626., 22 (Box 7)
    - Brouwer, Adriaen, 1605-1638., 39 (Box 7)
    - Bruegel, Jan the Elder, 1568-1625., 71 (Box 8)
      Includes School of Jan Bruegel the Elder.
      - Locations not noted., 23 (Box 8)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 35 (Box 8)
      - Amsterdam., 6 (Box 8)
      - Vienna., 7 (Box 8)
    - Brueghel, Jan the Younger, 1601-1678., 15 (Box 9)
    - Bruegel, Pieter the Elder, 1525-1569., 215 (Box 9)
      - Drawings., 9 (Box 9)
      - Paintings., 206 (Box 9)
        - Private collections., 5 (Box 9)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 48 (Box 9)
        - Antwerp., 8 (Box 10)
        - Brussels., 22 (Box 10)
        - London., 6 (Box 10)
        - New York., 7 (Box 10)
        - Vienna., 110 (Box 11)
          - Miscellaneous works., 14 (Box 11)
          - Children's Games., 13 (Box 11)
          - Christ Bearing the Cross., 14 (Box 11)
          - Contest Between Carnival and Lent., 14 (Box 11)
          - Conversion of St. Paul., 3 (Box 11)
          - Hunters in the Snow., 12 (Box 11)
          - Massacre of the Innocents., 10 (Box 12)
          - Peasant Dance., 7 (Box 12)
          - Peasant Wedding., 11 (Box 12)
          - Return of the Herd., 5 (Box 12)
          - Tower of Babel., 7 (Box 12)
    - Bruegel, Pieter the Younger, 1564-1637., 26 (Box 13)
    - Bueckelaer, Joachim, 1533-1573., 9 (Box 13)
- C (Box 13)
  - Miscellaneous Artists C., 28 (Box 13)
    - Candido, Pietro, 1548-1586., 2 (Box 13)
    - Casteels, Pieter, 1684-1749., 1 (Box 13)
    - Caullery, Louis de, active 1594-1620., 1 (Box 13)
    - Clerck, Hendrik de, 1570-1629., 1 (Box 13)
    - Cleve, Hendrick van, c.1525-1589., 1 (Box 13)
    - Cock, Jan Wellens de, 1506-1527., 4 (Box 13)
    - Coninxloo, Cornelius van, active 1529-1559., 2 (Box 13)
    - Coninxloo, Gilles van, 1544-1607., 4 (Box 13)
    - Cornelisz, L., 1493/5-1552., 1 (Box 13)
    - Cornelius van Amsterdam, c.1470-1533., 1 (Box 13)
    - Cossiers, Jan, 1600-1671., 4 (Box 13)
    - Coter, Colijn de, c.1455-1538., 3 (Box 13)
    - Coxcie, Michiel, 1540-1616., 2 (Box 13)
    - Custodis, Hieronimus, active 1589., 1 (Box 13)
  - Individual Artists C., 189 (Box 14)
    - Campin, Robert, 1374-1444., 57 (Box 14)
    - Christus, Petrus, active 1444-1473., 39 (Box 15)
    - Cleve, Joos van, 1485-1541., 59 (Box 16)
    - Coecke van Aelst, Pieter, 1502-1550., 6 (Box 16)
    - Coques, Gonzales, 1618-1684., 10 (Box 16)
    - Cornelisz, Jacob, 1460/70-1533., 6 (Box 16)
    - Craesbeek, Joos van, 1605-1661., 7 (Box 17)
      Name also spelled Craesbecke and Craesbeeck.
    - Crayer, Gaspard de, 1584-1669., 5 (Box 17)
- D (Box 17)
  - Miscellaneous Artists D., 11 (Box 17)
    - Dael, Jan Franz van, XVIII C., 1 (Box 17)
    - Dalem, Cornelis van, active 1545-1565., 4 (Box 17)
    - Denys, Jacob, 1644-after 1695., 1 (Box 17)
    - Diepenbeeck, Abraham van, 1596-1675., 1 (Box 17)
    - Dierickx, A., ?., 1 (Box 17)
    - Douffet, Gerard, 1594-1660., 1 (Box 17)
    - Duchatel, Francois, 1626-1671., 1 (Box 17)
    - Dyckmans, Josef Laurens, 1811-1888. (Box 17)
  - Individual Artists D., 66 (Box 17)
    - Daret, Jean, 1613-1668., 5 (Box 17)
    - David, Gerard, 1450-1523., 61 (Box 17)
- E (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous Artists E., 5 (Box 18)
    - Egmont, Justus van, 1601-1674., 2 (Box 18)
    - Ehrenbuerg, Willem von, 1603-1679., 1 (Box 18)
    - Ertvelt, Andries van, 1590-1652., 1 (Box 18)
      Name also spelled "Artvelt."
    - Esselens, Jacob, 1626-1687., 1 (Box 18)
  - Individual Artists E., 3 (Box 18)
    - Engelbrechtsz, Cornelis, c.1468-c.1533., 3 (Box 18)
- F (Box 18)
  - Miscellaneous Artists F., 7 (Box 18)
    - Flemalle, B., 1614-1675., 1 (Box 18)
    - Franchoys, Lucas the Younger, 1616-1681., 1 (Box 18)
    - Francken, Ambrosius, 1544-1618., 1 (Box 18)
    - Francken, Frans I, 1542-1616., 1 (Box 18)
    - Francken, Frans III, 1607-1667., 1 (Box 18)
    - Froment, Nicolas, 1425-1483., 1 (Box 18)
    - Fruytiers, Phillip, 1610-1666., 1 (Box 18)
  - Individual Artists F., 27 (Box 18)
    - Floris, Frans, 1529-1570., 9 (Box 18)
    - Francken, Frans II, 1581-1642., 7 (Box 18)
    - Fyt, Jan, 1611-1661., 11 (Box 18)
- G (Box 19)
  - Miscellaneous Artists G., 15 (Box 19)
    - Garemijn, Jan Anton, 1712-1799., 1 (Box 19)
    - Gassel, Lucas van, 1500-1570., 2 (Box 19)
    - Geldorp, George, 1610-1653., 1 (Box 19)
    - Geldorp, Gortzius, 1553-1618., 2 (Box 19)
    - Gheyn, Jacob de, XVI or XVII C., 1 (Box 19)
    - Goovaerts, Abraham, 1589-1626., 1 (Box 19)
    - Goubau, Antoine, 1616-1698., 1 (Box 19)
    - Grimmer, Abel, 1573-1619., 4 (Box 19)
    - Grimmer, Jacob, c.1526-1592., 1 (Box 19)
    - Gyseis, Peeter, 1621-1690., 1 (Box 19)
  - Individual Artists G, 62 (Box 19)
    - Gheeraerts, Marcus the Elder, 1516-1590, and the Younger, 1561-1635., 13 (Box 19)
    - Goes, Hugo van der, 1440-1482., 49 (Box 19)
      - Drawings., 4 (Box 19)
      - Paintings., 45 (Box 19)
- H (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous Artists H., 24 (Box 20)
    - Haecht, Willem van, 1593-1637., 2 (Box 20)
    - Heere, Lucas de, 1534-1584., 1 (Box 20)
    - Heeremansz, Frans, active c.1670., 1 (Box 20)
    - Helmon, Marcel, active 1580., 1 (Box 20)
    - Hemessen, Jan van, active 1500-1566., 4 (Box 20)
      Also known as Jan Sanders.
    - Hemessen, Katharina van, XVI C., 1 (Box 20)
    - Hesvroom, Jan, active 1660., 1 (Box 20)
    - Hoefnagel, Joris, 1542-1600., 1 (Box 20)
    - Horemans, Pieter Jacob, 1700-1776., 1 (Box 20)
    - Horenbout, Lucas, active 1525-1545., 1 (Box 20)
    - Hulsdonck, Jan van, 1582-1647., 3 (Box 20)
    - Huys, Pieter, 1519-1584., 4 (Box 20)
    - Huysmans, Cornelis, 1648-1727., 3 (Box 20)
  - Individual Artists H., 5 (Box 20)
    - Huysmans, Jacob, 1633-1696., 5 (Box 20)
- I (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous Artists I. (Box 20)
  - Individual Artists I., 22 (Box 20)
    - Isenbrant, Adriaen, active 1510-1551., 22 (Box 20)
- J (Box 20)
  - Miscellaneous Artists J., 9 (Box 20)
    - Janssens, Abraham, 1575-1732., 4 (Box 20)
    - Janssens, Cornelis, 1593/4-1662/4., 2 (Box 20)
    - Joest von Kalkar, J., 1460-1519., 1 (Box 20)
    - Jode, Pieter de, 1570-1634., 1 (Box 20)
    - Jordaens, Hans III, 1584-1644., 1 (Box 20)
    - Juan de Flandes, c. 1465-1519., 1 (Box 20)
  - Individual Artists J., 104 (Box 20)
    - Joos van Ghent, active 1460-1480., 25 (Box 20)
      Also known as Justus van Ghent.
    - Jordaens, Jacob, 1593-1678., 79 (Box 21)
      - Drawings., 8 (Box 21)
      - Paintings., 71 (Box 21)
      - Madrid. (Box 22)
- K (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous Artists K., 10 (Box 22)
    - Keirinkcx, Alexander, 1600-1652., 3 (Box 22)
    - Kessel, Ferdinand van, 1641-1680., 1 (Box 22)
    - Kessel, Jan van I, 1626-1699., 3 (Box 22)
    - Key, Adrian Thomasz, c.1544-c.1590., 1 (Box 22)
    - Key, Willem, -1568., 2 (Box 22)
- L (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous Artists L., 6 (Box 22)
    - Lombard, Lambert, 1506-1566., 3 (Box 22)
    - Loon, Theodore van, 1585-1660., 3 (Box 22)
  - Individual Artists L., 6 (Box 22)
    - Lint, Hendrik van, 1684-1763., 6 (Box 22)
- M (Box 22)
  - Miscellaneous Artists M., 9 (Box 22)
    - Mandyn, Jan, 1500-1560., 2 (Box 22)
    - Miel, Jan, 1599-1664., 1 (Box 22)
    - Minderhout, H., 1632-1696., 1 (Box 22)
    - Mirou, Anthonie, 1586-1620., 1 (Box 22)
    - Mol, Pieter, 1599-1650., 1 (Box 22)
    - Momper, Frans de, 1603-1660., 1 (Box 22)
    - Momper, Jodocus de, the Elder, 1603-1660., 1 (Box 22)
    - Monogrammist H.E., active 1569., 1 (Box 22)
    - Mostaert, Gillis, 1525-1598., 1 (Box 22)
  - Individual Artists M., 406 (Box 22)
    - Mabuse, Jan Gossaert, c.1470-1533., 99 (Box 22)
      - Drawings., 8 (Box 22)
      - Paintings., 91 (Box 23)
    - Mander, Karel van, 1548-1606., 4 (Box 24)
    - Massys, Cornelis, 1512-after 1580., 8 (Box 24)
    - Massys, Jan, 1510-1575., 3 (Box 24)
    - Massys, Quentin, 1466-1530., 71 (Box 24)
      Also known as Quentin Metsys.
      - Miscellaneous cities., 44 (Box 24)
      - Antwerp., 18 (Box 24)
      - Brussels., 9 (Box 25)
    - Memling, Hans, 1430-1494., 154 (Box 25)
      - Locations not noted., 10 (Box 25)
      - Miscellaneous cities., 45 (Box 25)
      - Bruges., 38 (Box 26)
      - London., 10 (Box 26)
      - Munich., 8 (Box 26)
      - New York., 22 (Box 26)
      - Washington., 17 (Box 27)
      - School of Memling., 4 (Box 27)
    - Meulen, Adam-Francois van der, 1632-1690., 7 (Box 27)
    - Momper, Joos de, the Younger, 1564-1635., 19 (Box 27)
    - Moro, Antonio, c.1512-1575., 41 (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous Cities A-M. (Box 27)
    - Miscellaneous Cities N-Z. (Box 28)
- N, O, P, Q (Box 28)
  - Miscellaneous Artists N, O, P, Q., 22 (Box 28)
    - Neefs, Pieter, 1577/78-1657/61., 4 (Box 28)
    - Neufchatel, Nicolas, 1525/7-1590., 1 (Box 28)
    - Neyts, Gillis, 1623-1687., 1 (Box 28)
    - Nieulandt, Adriaen van, 1587-1658., 2 (Box 28)
    - Noort, Adam van, the Elder, 1562-1641., 2 (Box 28)
    - Oost, Jacob, 1601-1671., 5 (Box 28)
    - Peeters, Bonaventura, 1614-1652., 3 (Box 28)
    - Peeters, Clara, c.1590-after 1657., 2 (Box 28)
    - Quellinus, Erasmus II, 1607-1678., 2 (Box 28)
  - Individual Artists N, O, P, Q., 93 (Box 28)
    - Orley, Bernard van, 1492-1542., 28 (Box 28)
    - Patinir, Joachim de, 1475-1524., 32 (Box 29)
    - Pourbus, Frans the Younger, 1570-1622., 16 (Box 29)
      Includes one painting by Frans Pourbus the Elder.
    - Pourbus, Pieter, 1510-1584., 8 (Box 29)
    - Provost, Jan, 1462-1529., 9 (Box 29)
- R (Box 30)
  - Miscellaneous Artists R., 12 (Box 30)
    - Rombouts, Theodore, 1596-1637., 5 (Box 30)
    - Roore, Jacques Ignatius de, 1686-1747., 1 (Box 30)
    - Ryckaert, David, 1612-1622., 4 (Box 30)
    - Rysbraeck, Pieter Andreas, 1690-1748., 2 (Box 30)
  - Individual Artists R, 1120 (Box 30)
    - Roymerswaele, Marinus van, 1493-1567., 12 (Box 30)
      Name also spelled Reymerswaele.
    - Rubens, Peter Paul, 1577-1640., 1108 (Box 30)
      - Drawings., 113 (Box 30)
        - Locations not noted., 26 (Box 30)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 46 (Box 31)
        - London., 29 (Box 31)
        - Vienna., 12 (Box 32)
      - Paintings., 995 (Box 32)
        - Locations not noted., 54 (Box 32)
          - Miscellaneous subjects., 5 (Box 32)
          - Biblical and Religious Themes., 19 (Box 32)
          - Mythological Themes., 9 (Box 32)
          - Portraits., 21 (Box 32)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 141 (Box 33-, Box 34)
        - Antwerp., 72 (Box 35)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 7 (Box 35)
          - Cathedral., 12 (Box 35)
          - Royal Museum., 53 (Box 35)
        - Bayonne., 13 (Box 35)
        - Berlin., 33 (Box 36)
        - Boston., 12 (Box 36)
        - Brussels., 54 (Box 37)
        - Cambridge, England., 10 (Box 37)
        - Cassel., 9 (Box 37)
        - Detroit., 10 (Box 37)
        - Dresden., 24 (Box 38)
        - Florence., 11 (Box 38)
        - Leningrad., 11 (Box 38)
        - London., 90 (Box 38-, Box 39)
        - Madrid., 60 (Box 40)
        - Munich., 118 (Box 41)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 4 (Box 41)
          - Alte Pinakothek., 114 (Box 41)
            - Miscellaneous subjects., 27 (Box 41)
            - Landscapes., 8 (Box 41)
            - Marie de Medici sketches., 21 (Box 41)
            - Portraits., 29 (Box 42)
            - Religious/biblical scenes., 28 (Box 42)
        - New York., 32 (Box 43)
        - Paris., 74 (Box 43)
          - Miscellaneous subjects., 22 (Box 43)
          - History of Marie de Medici., 52 (Box 44)
        - Philadelphia., 13 (Box 45)
        - Rotterdam., 31 (Box 45)
        - Vaduz., 27 (Box 45)
        - Vienna., 71 (Box 46)
          - Miscellaneous locations., 2 (Box 46)
          - Kunsthistorischen Museums., 69 (Box 46)
            - Miscellaneous subjects., 21 (Box 46)
            - Portraits., 21 (Box 46)
            - Religious/biblical scenes., 27 (Box 46)
        - Washington, D.C., 25 (Box 46)
- S (Box 47)
  - Miscellaneous Artists S., 24 (Box 47)
    - Sallaert, Antonie, c.1590-c.1658., 2 (Box 47)
    - Schoubroeck, Pieter, XVI C., 1 (Box 47)
    - Schuppen, Jakob von, 1670-1751., 1 (Box 47)
    - Schut, Cornelis I, 1597-1655., 1 (Box 47)
    - Seghers, Gerard, 1589-1651., 3 (Box 47)
    - Shayers, Pieter, 1593-after 1669., 1 (Box 47)
    - Speckaert, Hans, -1577., 2 (Box 47)
      Name also spelled Speeckaert.
    - Stalbemt, Adriaen, 1580-1662., 1 (Box 47)
    - Steenwyck, Hendrick van, 1580-1649., 3 (Box 47)
    - Stevens, Pieter, 1540-1620., 1 (Box 47)
    - Stomer, Matthias, c.1600-c.1650., 4 (Box 47)
    - Straet, Jan van der, 1523-1605., 1 (Box 47)
    - Streater, Robert, 1624-1680., 1 (Box 47)
    - Swart, Jan, 1469-1535., 1 (Box 47)
  - Individual Artists S., 97 (Box 47)
    - Savery, Roelant, 1576-1639., 29 (Box 47)
    - Seghers, Daniel, 1590-1661., 6 (Box 47)
    - Siberechts, Jan, 1627-1700., 9 (Box 47)
    - Sithium, Miguel, 1469-1525., 9 (Box 47)
    - Snyders, Frans, 1579-1657., 20 (Box 48)
    - Spanger, Bartholomaus, 1546-1611., 9 (Box 48)
    - Sustermans, Justus, 1597-1681., 15 (Box 48)
- T (Box 48)
  - Miscellaneous Artists T., 5 (Box 48)
    - Thulden, Theodore van, 1606-1669., 2 (Box 48)
    - Tilborgh, Gillis van, 1625-1675., 2 (Box 48)
      Name also spelled Tilborch.
    - Tyssens, Gysbrecht, 1616-1684., 1 (Box 48)
  - Individual Artists T., 91 (Box 48)
    - Teniers, David the Elder, 1582-1649., 5 (Box 48)
    - Teniers, David the Younger, 1610-1690., 86 (Box 49)
- U, V (Box 50)
  - Miscellaneous Artists U, V., 19 (Box 50)
    - Uden, Lucas van, 1595-1673., 4 (Box 50)
    - Utrecht, Adriaen, 1599-1652., 1 (Box 50)
    - Vadder, L. de, 1605-1655., 2 (Box 50)
    - Vaillant, Wallerant, 1623-1677., 2 (Box 50)
    - Valckenborch, Frederik van, 1570-1623., 2 (Box 50)
    - Van Eych, Kasper, 1613-1673., 1 (Box 50)
    - Van Leen, Willem, 1753-1825., 1 (Box 50)
    - Veen, Otho van, 1558-1629., 1 (Box 50)
    - Vellert, Dirck, active 1511-1544., 3 (Box 50)
    - Verendael, Nicholas van, 1640-1691., 1 (Box 50)
    - Vos, Simon de, 1603-1676., 1 (Box 50)
  - Individual Artists U, V., 810 (Box 50)
    - Valckenborch, Lucas van, c.1530-1597., 7 (Box 50)
    - Van der Weyden, Goswin, 1465-after 1538., 7 (Box 50)
    - Van der Weyden, Roger, 1400-1464., 128 (Box 50)
      - Drawings., 3 (Box 50)
      - Paintings., 125 (Box 50)
        - Locations not noted and private collections., 3 (Box 50)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 63 (Box 50-, Box 51)
        - Berlin., 13 (Box 51)
        - Madrid., 13 (Box 51)
        - Munich., 12 (Box 52)
        - New York., 21 (Box 52)
    - Van Dyck, Anthony, 1599-1644., 463 (Box 52)
      - Drawings., 28 (Box 52)
      - Paintings., 435 (Box 53)
        - Locations not noted and private collections., 75 (Box 53)
          - Miscellaneous subjects., 13 (Box 53)
          - Portraits of men., 36 (Box 53)
          - Portraits of women., 26 (Box 53)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 117 (Box 53-, Box 54)
        - Berlin., 15 (Box 55)
        - Dresden., 16 (Box 55)
        - Leningrad/St. Petersburg., 10 (Box 55)
        - London., 72 (Box 56)
          - Miscellaneous subjects., 19 (Box 56)
          - Portraits., 53 (Box 56)
        - Munich., 23 (Box 57)
        - New York., 33 (Box 57)
        - Paris., 12 (Box 57)
        - Vienna., 30 (Box 58)
        - Washington., 32 (Box 58)
    - Van Eyck, Jan and/or Hubert, 1390-1440, 1366-1426., 175 (Box 59)
      - Drawings., 4 (Box 59)
      - Paintings., 171 (Box 59)
        - Locations not noted., 4 (Box 59)
        - Miscellaneous cities., 43 (Box 59)
        - Ghent Altarpiece., 66 (Box 60)
          - Closed., 18 (Box 60)
          - Open., 48 (Box 60)
        - Berlin., 13 (Box 61)
        - Bruges., 10 (Box 61)
        - London., 19 (Box 61)
        - New York., 16 (Box 61)
    - Vos, Cornelis de, 1585-1651., 23 (Box 62)
    - Vos, Paulus de or Maerten de, c.1600-1654, 1532-1603., 7 (Box 62)
- W (Box 62)
  - Miscellaneous Artists W., 8 (Box 62)
    - Wael, Cornelis de, 1592-1667., 1 (Box 62)
    - Wiertz, Antoine, 1806-1865., 1 (Box 62)
    - Wildens, Jan, 1586-1653., 3 (Box 62)
    - Willeborts, Thomas, 1614-1654., 1 (Box 62)
      Also known as Bosschaert.
    - Winghe, Joos van, 1544-1603., 2 (Box 62)